David Annez

Frontend developer

Website Portfolio www.davidannez.com

LinkedIn Nationality Current Location linkedin.com/in/davidannez Belgian/British Glasgow, Scotland

I'm an imaginative and creative frontend web developer and designer with commercial and freelance experience.

I deliver cross browser compliant, usable websites that use the latest technologies (specifically HTML5/CSS3) whilst ensuring a consistent experience for all users.

I've worked in many different work sectors and have a strong grasp of brand identity, UX/UI and eCommerce systems.

I've got over 6 years experience with web development/design and work quickly and proficiently.

Key Skills

Frontend website development (CSS3/HTML5)

Web Development/Design Tools

Photoshop

eCommerce.

Illustrator

InDesign

Ruby / Ruby on Rails

PHP / MYSQL

HTML5 / CSS3

jQuery / AJAX / Javascript

Magento / eCommerce

Linux

Interests

Photography, Music, Design, Football

Languages

Fluent Spanish, Catalan and French

Experience

Jan 2012 ~

Senior Frontend Developer - Tictoc Family Ltd

Working with the latest web technologies - Responsive design, mobile apps, HAML, SASS, Retina display ready websites. Worked on over 30 different websites ranging from charities to construction companies. Pushing the boundaries of frontend web development with HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript. Continuous interaction with backend/design to ensure a seamless end product.

2011 ~

Founder/Director - Frogbeats LTD

Started up a small limited company selling high quality earphones to students and audiophiles. Responsible for the development of the website; the branding; financial aspects and the general management of the company as founder and director. Worked on UI/UX and user journeys to ensure a seamless experience when selling products through our websites.

2006 ~

Web developer - Arktive/Freelance

Started up web development company back in 2006 - Working on PHP/Rails based sites. Both development and design work was undertaken, and sometimes worked in a team with fellow designers. Worked as a consultant and developer for Citizen's Advice Bureau, The Pirate Bay and BF2s. Focus on existing PHP frameworks such as Codelgniter and Kohana sticking to OO MVC standards. W3C standards always met and have a good reputation behind eCommerce websites (developed mainly in Magento).

2008 - 2009

Civil Engineer Undergraduate - Network Rail

Worked with the Civil Engineering Dept. at Network Rail - Dealing with civil engineering drawings; presentations and analysis of specific weather data. Essential time management skills were learnt and dealing with other teams as well as working individually.

2010 ~

Mentor - Innovative Routes to Learning, Strathclyde University

Worked as a Mentor to 3rd, 4th and 6th years in Secondary School through the Innovative Routes to Learning course. This course was designed to help youngsters apply themselves in school so they can go on to higher education and university.

2009 - 2011 Jacksons Western Store

2009 - 2010 Citizens Advice Bureau

2007 - 2008 SQA temporary experience with web developers

Education

2010 ~ The University of Glasgow - Product Design Engineering 2008 - 2009 : Perth College - CMI Management Degree